<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en"
   >
  <title type="text">#gitfr</title>
  <subtitle type="text">Projet pour la promotion du bien et la destruction du mal</subtitle>

  <updated>2013-01-06T01:34:24Z</updated>
  <generator uri="http://blogofile.com/">Blogofile</generator>

  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.gitfr.net/blog" />
  <id>http://www.gitfr.net/blog/feed/atom/</id>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.gitfr.net/blog/feed/atom/" />
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name></name>
      <uri>http://www.gitfr.net/blog</uri>
    </author>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git 1.8.0 publiée]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2013/01/06/git-1.8.0-publiee" />
    <id>http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2013/01/06/git-1.8.0-publiee</id>
    <updated>2013-01-06T21:43:00Z</updated>
    <published>2013-01-06T21:43:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.gitfr.net/blog" term="release" />
    <category scheme="http://www.gitfr.net/blog" term="git" />
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Git 1.8.0 publiée]]></summary>
    <content type="html" xml:base="http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2013/01/06/git-1.8.0-publiee"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Note</strong> : Git 1.8.0 est sortie le 22 octobre, désolé pour le retard.</p>
<p>Changements intéressants:
 * la configuration upstream d'une branche évolue: --set-upstream est dépréciée,
   et est remplacée par --set-upstream-to=reference.
   Au delà du changement de nom, c'est la syntaxe qui évolue pour être plus simple
   et plus logique.
   En effet, avec --set-upstream, vous deviez taper:</p>
<p><code>git branch --set-upstream my-branch origin/dev</code></p>
<p>--set-upstream est un flag, qui précise que le refspec de base de la branche
   créée est aussi l'upstream. Ce n'est pas évident, et l'on aurait tendance à
   interpréter la commande dans l'autre sens, dans la tradition des commandes Unix.
   Avec la nouvelle syntaxe, on tape:</p>
<p><code>git branch --set-upstream-to=origin/dev my-branch</code></p>
<p>Cette syntaxe est bien plus compréhensible. L'ancienne syntaxe est dépréciée.
   Si vous ne connaissez toujours pas les magies et bienfaits des branches upstream,
   je vous invite à (re)lire
   <a href="http://gitfr.net/blog/2011/12/11/comportement-par-defaut-du-git-push/">ce billet</a>.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>git cherry-pick respecte désormais l'ordre des commits tels que passés en arguments.
   Précédemment, il rejouait les commits suivant la chronologie de commit.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>git blame est désormais plus précis lors des merge : il reconnait les conflits
   résolus comme venant d'un des commits parents plutôt que simplement étant des
   modifications non committées (sha1=0000000)</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>N'hésitez pas comme d'habitude à commenter ce billet si vous voyez des
changements intéressants.</p>
<h2>Changelog</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>A credential helper for Win32 to allow access to the keychain of
   the logged-in user has been added.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>An initial port to HP NonStop.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A credential helper to allow access to the Gnome keyring has been
   added.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>When "git am" sanitizes the "Subject:" line, we strip the prefix from
   "Re: subject" and also from a less common "re: subject", but left
   the even less common "RE: subject" intact.  Now we strip that too.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>It was tempting to say "git branch --set-upstream origin/master",
   but that tells Git to arrange the local branch "origin/master" to
   integrate with the currently checked out branch, which is highly
   unlikely what the user meant.  The option is deprecated; use the
   new "--set-upstream-to" (with a short-and-sweet "-u") option
   instead.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git cherry-pick" learned the "--allow-empty-message" option to
   allow it to replay a commit without any log message.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>After "git cherry-pick -s" gave control back to the user asking
   help to resolve conflicts, concluding "git commit" used to need to
   be run with "-s" if the user wants to sign it off; now the command
   leaves the sign-off line in the log template.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git daemon" learned the "--access-hook" option to allow an
   external command to decline service based on the client address,
   repository path, etc.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git difftool --dir-diff" learned to use symbolic links to prepare
   a temporary copy of the working tree when available.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git grep" learned to use a non-standard pattern type by default if
   a configuration variable tells it to.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Accumulated updates to "git gui" has been merged.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git log -g" learned the "--grep-reflog=<pattern>" option to limit
   its output to commits with a reflog message that matches the given
   pattern.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git merge-base" learned the "--is-ancestor A B" option to tell if A is
   an ancestor of B.  The result is indicated by its exit status code.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git mergetool" now allows users to override the actual command used
   with the mergetool.$name.cmd configuration variable even for built-in
   mergetool backends.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git rebase -i" learned the "--edit-todo" option to open an editor
   to edit the instruction sheet.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git svn" has been updated to work with SVN 1.7.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git p4" learned the "--conflicts" option to specify what to do when
   encountering a conflict during "p4 submit".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Git ships with a fall-back regexp implementation for platforms with
   buggy regexp library, but it was easy for people to keep using their
   platform regexp by mistake.  A new test has been added to check this.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The "check-docs" build target has been updated and greatly
   simplified.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The test suite is run under MALLOC_CHECK_ when running with a glibc
   that supports the feature.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The documentation in the TeXinfo format was using indented output
   for materials meant to be examples that are better typeset in
   monospace.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Compatibility wrapper around some mkdir(2) implementations that
   reject parameters with trailing slash has been introduced.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Compatibility wrapper for systems that lack usable setitimer() has
   been added.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The option parsing of "git checkout" had error checking, dwim and
   defaulting missing options, all mixed in the code, and issuing an
   appropriate error message with useful context was getting harder.
   The code has been reorganized to allow giving a proper diagnosis
   when the user says "git checkout -b -t foo bar" (e.g. "-t" is not a
   good name for a branch).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Many internal uses of a "git merge-base" equivalent were only to see
   if one commit fast-forwards to the other, which did not need the
   full set of merge bases to be computed. They have been updated to
   use less expensive checks.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The heuristics to detect and silently convert latin1 to utf8 when
   we were told to use utf-8 in the log message has been transplanted
   from "mailinfo" to "commit" and "commit-tree".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Messages given by "git <subcommand> -h" from many subcommands have
   been marked for translation.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The attribute system may be asked for a path that itself or its
   leading directories no longer exists in the working tree, and it is
   fine if we cannot open .gitattribute file in such a case.  Failure
   to open per-directory .gitattributes with error status other than
   ENOENT and ENOTDIR should be diagnosed, but it wasn't.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>When looking for $HOME/.gitconfig etc., it is OK if we cannot read
   them because they do not exist, but we did not diagnose existing
   files that we cannot read.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>When "git am" is fed an input that has multiple "Content-type: ..."
   header, it did not grok charset= attribute correctly.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git am" mishandled a patch attached as application/octet-stream
   (e.g. not text/*); Content-Transfer-Encoding (e.g. base64) was not
   honored correctly.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git blame MAKEFILE" run in a history that has "Makefile" but not
   "MAKEFILE" should say "No such file MAKEFILE in HEAD", but got
   confused on a case insensitive filesystem and failed to do so.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Even during a conflicted merge, "git blame $path" always meant to
   blame uncommitted changes to the "working tree" version; make it
   more useful by showing cleanly merged parts as coming from the other
   branch that is being merged.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>It was unclear in the documentation for "git blame" that it is
   unnecessary for users to use the "--follow" option.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Output from "git branch -v" contains "(no branch)" that could be
   localized, but the code to align it along with the names of
   branches was counting in bytes, not in display columns.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git cherry-pick A C B" used to replay changes in A and then B and
   then C if these three commits had committer timestamps in that
   order, which is not what the user who said "A C B" naturally
   expects.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A repository created with "git clone --single" had its fetch
   refspecs set up just like a clone without "--single", leading the
   subsequent "git fetch" to slurp all the other branches, defeating
   the whole point of specifying "only this branch".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Documentation talked about "first line of commit log" when it meant
   the title of the commit.  The description was clarified by defining
   how the title is decided and rewording the casual mention of "first
   line" to "title".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git cvsimport" did not thoroughly cleanse tag names that it
   inferred from the names of the tags it obtained from CVS, which
   caused "git tag" to barf and stop the import in the middle.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Earlier we made the diffstat summary line that shows the number of
   lines added/deleted localizable, but it was found irritating having
   to see them in various languages on a list whose discussion language
   is English, and this change has been reverted.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git fetch --all", when passed "--no-tags", did not honor the
   "--no-tags" option while fetching from individual remotes (the same
   issue existed with "--tags", but the combination "--all --tags" makes
   much less sense than "--all --no-tags").</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git fetch" over http had an old workaround for an unlikely server
   misconfiguration; it turns out that this hurts debuggability of the
   configuration in general, and has been reverted.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git fetch" over http advertised that it supports "deflate", which
   is much less common, and did not advertise the more common "gzip" on
   its Accept-Encoding header.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git fetch" over the dumb-http revision walker could segfault when
   curl's multi interface was used.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git gc --auto" notified the user that auto-packing has triggered
    even under the "--quiet" option.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>After "gitk" showed the contents of a tag, neither "Reread
   references" nor "Reload" updated what is shown as the
   contents of it when the user overwrote the tag with "git tag -f".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git log --all-match --grep=A --grep=B" ought to show commits that
   mention both A and B, but when these three options are used with
   --author or --committer, it showed commits that mention either A or
   B (or both) instead.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The "-Xours" backend option to "git merge -s recursive" was ignored
   for binary files.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git p4", when "--use-client-spec" and "--detect-branches" are used
   together, misdetected branches.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git receive-pack" (the counterpart to "git push") did not give
   progress output while processing objects it received to the puser
   when run over the smart-http protocol.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>When you misspell the command name you give to the "exec" action in
   the "git rebase -i" instruction sheet you were told that 'rebase' is not a
   git subcommand from "git rebase --continue".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The subcommand in "git remote" to remove a defined remote was
   "rm" and the command did not take a fully-spelled "remove".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The interactive prompt that "git send-email" gives was error prone. It
   asked "What e-mail address do you want to use?" with the address it
   guessed (correctly) the user would want to use in its prompt,
   tempting the user to say "y". But the response was taken as "No,
   please use 'y' as the e-mail address instead", which is most
   certainly not what the user meant.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git show --format='%ci'" did not give the timestamp correctly for
   commits created without human readable name on the "committer" line.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git show --quiet" ought to be a synonym for "git show -s", but
   wasn't.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git submodule frotz" was not diagnosed as "frotz" being an unknown
   subcommand to "git submodule"; the user instead got a complaint
   that "git submodule status" was run with an unknown path "frotz".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git status" honored the ignore=dirty settings in .gitmodules but
   "git commit" didn't.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"gitweb" did not give the correct committer timezone in its feed
   output due to a typo.</p>
</li>
</ul>]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name></name>
      <uri>http://www.gitfr.net/blog</uri>
    </author>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git 1.7.12 publiée]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2012/08/24/git-1.7.12-publiee" />
    <id>http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2012/08/24/git-1.7.12-publiee</id>
    <updated>2012-08-24T02:54:00Z</updated>
    <published>2012-08-24T02:54:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.gitfr.net/blog" term="release" />
    <category scheme="http://www.gitfr.net/blog" term="git" />
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Git 1.7.12 publiée]]></summary>
    <content type="html" xml:base="http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2012/08/24/git-1.7.12-publiee"><![CDATA[<p>Quatre changements intéressants dans cette 1.7.12 qui date du 20 août :</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Une option <code>--root</code> à rebase pour modifier aussi le commit root.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Une option <code>-x</code> à rebase pour éxécuter une commande à chaque
  application d'un patch.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>On peut visualiser la documentation en HTML avec <code>git help -w $cmd</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>git status</code> est plus précis quand le dépôt est dans un état
  intermédiaire (lors d'un merge, un rebase, etc).</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>N'hésitez pas comme d'habitude à commenter ce billet si vous voyez des 
changements intéressants.</p>
<h2>Le changelog</h2>
<ul>
<li>Git can be told to normalize pathnames it read from readdir(3) and
   all arguments it got from the command line into precomposed UTF-8
   (assuming that they come as decomposed UTF-8), in order to work
   around issues on Mac OS.</li>
</ul>
<p>I think there still are other places that need conversion
   (e.g. paths that are read from stdin for some commands), but this
   should be a good first step in the right direction.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Per-user $HOME/.gitconfig file can optionally be stored in
   $HOME/.config/git/config instead, which is in line with XDG.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The value of core.attributesfile and core.excludesfile default to
   $HOME/.config/git/attributes and $HOME/.config/git/ignore respectively
   when these files exist.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Logic to disambiguate abbreviated object names have been taught to
   take advantage of object types that are expected in the context,
   e.g. XXXXXX in the "git describe" output v1.2.3-gXXXXXX must be a
   commit object, not a blob nor a tree.  This will help us prolong
   the lifetime of abbreviated object names.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git apply" learned to wiggle the base version and perform three-way
   merge when a patch does not exactly apply to the version you have.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Scripted Porcelain writers now have access to the credential API via
   the "git credential" plumbing command.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git help" used to always default to "man" format even on platforms
   where "man" viewer is not widely available.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git clone --local $path" started its life as an experiment to
   optionally use link/copy when cloning a repository on the disk, but
   we didn't deprecate it after we made the option a no-op to always
   use the optimization.  The command learned "--no-local" option to
   turn this off, as a more explicit alternative over use of file://
   URL.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git fetch" and friends used to say "remote side hung up
   unexpectedly" when they failed to get response they expect from the
   other side, but one common reason why they don't get expected
   response is that the remote repository does not exist or cannot be
   read. The error message in this case was updated to give better
   hints to the user.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git help -w $cmd" can show HTML version of documentation for
   "git-$cmd" by setting help.htmlpath to somewhere other than the
   default location where the build procedure installs them locally;
   the variable can even point at a http:// URL.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git rebase [-i] --root $tip" can now be used to rewrite all the
   history leading to "$tip" down to the root commit.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git rebase -i" learned "-x <cmd>" to insert "exec <cmd>" after
   each commit in the resulting history.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git status" gives finer classification to various states of paths
   in conflicted state and offer advice messages in its output.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git submodule" learned to deal with nested submodule structure
   where a module is contained within a module whose origin is
   specified as a relative URL to its superproject's origin.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A rather heavy-ish "git completion" script has been split to create
   a separate "git prompting" script, to help lazy-autoloading of the
   completion part while making prompting part always available.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"gitweb" pays attention to various forms of credits that are
   similar to "Signed-off-by:" lines in the commit objects and
   highlights them accordingly.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"mediawiki" remote helper (in contrib/) learned to handle file
   attachments.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git p4" now uses "Jobs:" and "p4 move" when appropriate.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>vcs-svn has been updated to clean-up compilation, lift 32-bit
   limitations, etc.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Some tests showed false failures caused by a bug in ecryptofs.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>We no longer use AsciiDoc7 syntax in our documentation and favor a
   more modern style.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git am --rebasing" codepath was taught to grab authorship, log
   message and the patch text directly out of existing commits.  This
   will help rebasing commits that have confusing "diff" output in
   their log messages.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git index-pack" and "git pack-objects" use streaming API to read
   from the object store to avoid having to hold a large blob object
   in-core while they are doing their thing.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Code to match paths with exclude patterns learned to avoid calling
   fnmatch() by comparing fixed leading substring literally when
   possible.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git log -n 1 -- rarely-touched-path" was spending unnecessary
   cycles after showing the first change to find the next one, only to
   discard it.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git svn" got a large-looking code reorganization at the last
   minute before the code freeze.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git submodule add" was confused when the superproject did not have
   its repository in its usual place in the working tree and GIT_DIR
   and GIT_WORK_TREE was used to access it.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git commit --amend" let the user edit the log message and then died
   when the human-readable committer name was given insufficiently by
   getpwent(3).</p>
</li>
</ul>]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name></name>
      <uri>http://www.gitfr.net/blog</uri>
    </author>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git 1.7.11 publiée]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2012/07/01/git-1.7.11-publiee" />
    <id>http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2012/07/01/git-1.7.11-publiee</id>
    <updated>2012-07-01T02:52:00Z</updated>
    <published>2012-07-01T02:52:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.gitfr.net/blog" term="release" />
    <category scheme="http://www.gitfr.net/blog" term="git" />
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Git 1.7.11 publiée]]></summary>
    <content type="html" xml:base="http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2012/07/01/git-1.7.11-publiee"><![CDATA[<p>Deux changements intéressants dans cette 1.7.11 qui date du 18 juin :</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Fini la configuration par défaut qui pousse toutes les branches connues
  sur le serveur. C'est maintenant le mode <em>simple</em> qui prend le relais,
  mode qui ne pousse (si et seulement si elle possède un nom identique sur le
  serveur) que le branche courante. C'est une configuration bien plus
  pertinente pour les débutants. Néanmoins je vous préconise <strong>le mode
  upstream</strong> comme dit dans
  <a href="http://gitfr.net/blog/2011/12/11/comportement-par-defaut-du-git-push/">ce billet</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Un outil en shell du nom de <em>git-subtree.sh</em> est ajoutée dans la section
  contrib, outil qui simplifie le découpage ou la fusion de dépôt. Cela
  permet par exemple de se dispenser de submodules en intégrant un dépôt
  dans un autre dépôt.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>N'hésitez pas comme d'habitude à commenter ce billet si vous voyez des 
changements intéressants.</p>
<h2>Le changelog</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>A new mode for push, "simple", which is a cross between "current"
  and "upstream", has been introduced. "git push" without any refspec
  will push the current branch out to the same name at the remote
  repository only when it is set to track the branch with the same
  name over there.  The plan is to make this mode the new default
  value when push.default is not configured.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A couple of commands learned the "--column" option to produce
  columnar output.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A third-party tool "git subtree" is distributed in contrib/</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A remote helper that acts as a proxy and caches ssl session for the
  https:// transport is added to the contrib/ area.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Error messages given when @{u} is used for a branch without its
  upstream configured have been clarified.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Even with the "-q"uiet option, "checkout" used to report setting up
  tracking.  Also "branch" learned the "-q"uiet option to squelch
  informational message.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Your build platform may support hardlinks but you may prefer not to
  use them, e.g. when installing to DESTDIR to make a tarball and
  untarring on a filesystem that has poor support for hardlinks.
  There is a Makefile option NO_INSTALL_HARDLINKS for you.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The smart-http backend used to always override GIT_COMMITTER_*
  variables with REMOTE_USER and REMOTE_ADDR, but these variables are
  now preserved when set.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git am" learned the "--include" option, which is an opposite of
  existing the "--exclude" option.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>When "git am -3" needs to fall back to an application of the patch
  to a synthesized preimage followed by a 3-way merge, the paths that
  needed such treatment are now reported to the end user, so that the
  result in them can be eyeballed with extra care.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The output from "diff/log --stat" used to always allocate 4 columns
  to show the number of modified lines, but not anymore.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git difftool" learned the "--dir-diff" option to spawn external
  diff tools that can compare two directory hierarchies at a time
  after populating two temporary directories, instead of running an
  instance of the external tool once per a file pair.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The "fmt-merge-msg" command learned to list the primary contributors
  involved in the side topic you are merging in a comment in the merge
  commit template.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git rebase" learned to optionally keep commits that do not
  introduce any change in the original history.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git push --recurse-submodules" learned to optionally look into the
  histories of submodules bound to the superproject and push them
  out.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A 'snapshot' request to "gitweb" honors If-Modified-Since: header,
  based on the commit date.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"gitweb" learned to highlight the patch it outputs even more.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git svn" used to die with unwanted SIGPIPE when talking with an HTTP
  server that uses keep-alive.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git svn" learned to use platform specific authentication
  providers, e.g. gnome-keyring, kwallet, etc.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git p4" has been moved out of the contrib/ area and has seen more
  work on importing labels as tags from (and exporting tags as labels
  to) p4.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Bash completion script (in contrib/) have been cleaned up to make
  future work on it simpler.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>An experimental "version 4" format of the index file has been
  introduced to reduce on-disk footprint and I/O overhead.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git archive" learned to produce its output without reading the
  blob object it writes out in memory in its entirety.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git index-pack" that runs when fetching or pushing objects to
  complete the packfile on the receiving end learned to use multiple
  threads to do its job when available.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The code to compute hash values for lines used by the internal diff
  engine was optimized on little-endian machines, using the same
  trick the kernel folks came up with.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git apply" had some memory leaks plugged.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Setting up a revision traversal with many starting points was
  inefficient as these were placed in a date-order priority queue
  one-by-one.  Now they are collected in the queue unordered first,
  and sorted immediately before getting used.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>More lower-level commands learned to use the streaming API to read
  from the object store without keeping everything in core.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The weighting parameters to suggestion command name typo have been
  tweaked, so that "git tags" will suggest "tag?" and not "stage?".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Because "sh" on the user's PATH may be utterly broken on some
  systems, run-command API now uses SHELL_PATH, not /bin/sh, when
  spawning an external command (not applicable to Windows port).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The API to iterate over the refs/ hierarchy has been tweaked to
  allow walking only a subset of it more efficiently.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git submodule init" used to report "registered for path ..."
  even for submodules that were registered earlier.
  (cherry-pick c1c259e jl/submodule-report-new-path-once later to maint).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git diff --stat" used to fully count a binary file with modified
  execution bits whose contents is unmodified, which was not quite
  right.</p>
</li>
</ul>]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name></name>
      <uri>http://www.gitfr.net/blog</uri>
    </author>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git 1.7.10 publiée]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2012/04/15/git-1.7.10-publiee" />
    <id>http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2012/04/15/git-1.7.10-publiee</id>
    <updated>2012-04-15T22:52:00Z</updated>
    <published>2012-04-15T22:52:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.gitfr.net/blog" term="release" />
    <category scheme="http://www.gitfr.net/blog" term="git" />
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Git 1.7.10 publiée]]></summary>
    <content type="html" xml:base="http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2012/04/15/git-1.7.10-publiee"><![CDATA[<p>Pas mal de petites changements dans cette version 1.7.10 sortie le 10 avril. Je
voulais initialement tester cette version avant de publier l'annonce mais je
n'ai pas eu le cou^H^H^Htemps :(. Mais rapidement de ce qu'ai pu voir :</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>gitk a pas mal de petites évolutions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Un éditeur s'ouvre lors d'un <code>git-commit</code> pour pousser les gens à expliquer
  les changements.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>On peut cloner qu'un répertoire.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>N'hésitez pas comme d'habitude à commenter ce billet si vous voyez des 
changements intéressants dans votre façon de travailler avec Git.</p>
<h2>Le changelog</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>various "gitk" updates.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Teams for localizing the messages from the Porcelain layer of
  commands are starting to form, thanks to Jiang Xin who volunteered
  to be the localization coordinator.  Translated messages for
  simplified Chinese, Swedish and Portuguese are available.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The configuration mechanism learned an "include" facility; an
  assignment to the include.path pseudo-variable causes the named
  file to be included in-place when Git looks up configuration
  variables.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A content filter (clean/smudge) used to be just a way to make the
  recorded contents "more useful", and allowed to fail; a filter can
  now optionally be marked as "required".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Options whose names begin with "--no-" (e.g. the "--no-verify"
  option of the "git commit" command) can be negated by omitting
  "no-" from its name, e.g. "git commit --verify".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git am" learned to pass "-b" option to underlying "git mailinfo", so
  that a bracketed string other than "PATCH" at the beginning can be kept.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git clone" learned "--single-branch" option to limit cloning to a
  single branch (surprise!); tags that do not point into the history
  of the branch are not fetched.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git clone" learned to detach the HEAD in the resulting repository
  when the user specifies a tag with "--branch" (e.g., "--branch=v1.0").
  Clone also learned to print the usual "detached HEAD" advice in such
  a case, similar to "git checkout v1.0".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>When showing a patch while ignoring whitespace changes, the context
  lines are taken from the postimage, in order to make it easier to
  view the output.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git diff --stat" learned to adjust the width of the output on
  wider terminals, and give more columns to pathnames as needed.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"diff-highlight" filter (in contrib/) was updated to produce more
  aesthetically pleasing output.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"fsck" learned "--no-dangling" option to omit dangling object
  information.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git log -G" and "git log -S" learned to pay attention to the "-i"
  option.  With "-i", "log -G" ignores the case when finding patch
  hunks that introduce or remove a string that matches the given
  pattern.  Similarly with "-i", "log -S" ignores the case when
  finding the commit the given block of text appears or disappears
  from the file.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git merge" in an interactive session learned to spawn the editor
  by default to let the user edit the auto-generated merge message,
  to encourage people to explain their merges better. Legacy scripts
  can export GIT_MERGE_AUTOEDIT=no to retain the historical behavior.
  Both "git merge" and "git pull" can be given --no-edit from the
  command line to accept the auto-generated merge message.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The advice message given when the user didn't give enough clue on
  what to merge to "git pull" and "git merge" has been updated to
  be more concise and easier to understand.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git push" learned the "--prune" option, similar to "git fetch".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The whole directory that houses a top-level superproject managed by
  "git submodule" can be moved to another place.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git symbolic-ref" learned the "--short" option to abbreviate the
  refname it shows unambiguously.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git tag --list" can be given "--points-at <object>" to limit its
  output to those that point at the given object.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"gitweb" allows intermediate entries in the directory hierarchy
  that leads to a project to be clicked, which in turn shows the
  list of projects inside that directory.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"gitweb" learned to read various pieces of information for the
  repositories lazily, instead of reading everything that could be
  needed (including the ones that are not necessary for a specific
  task).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Project search in "gitweb" shows the substring that matched in the
  project name and description highlighted.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>HTTP transport learned to authenticate with a proxy if needed.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A new script "diffall" is added to contrib/; it drives an
  external tool to perform a directory diff of two Git revisions
  in one go, unlike "difftool" that compares one file at a time.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Improved handling of views, labels and branches in "git-p4" (in contrib).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git-p4" (in contrib) suffered from unnecessary merge conflicts when
  p4 expanded the embedded $RCS$-like keywords; it can be now told to
  unexpand them.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Some "git-svn" updates.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"vcs-svn"/"svn-fe" learned to read dumps with svn-deltas and
  support incremental imports.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git difftool/mergetool" learned to drive DeltaWalker.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Unnecessary calls to parse_object() "git upload-pack" makes in
  response to "git fetch", have been eliminated, to help performance
  in repositories with excessive number of refs.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Recursive call chains in "git index-pack" to deal with long delta
  chains have been flattened, to reduce the stack footprint.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Use of add_extra_ref() API is now gone, to make it possible to
  cleanly restructure the overall refs API.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The command line parser of "git pack-objects" now uses parse-options
  API.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The test suite supports the new "test_pause" helper function.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Parallel to the test suite, there is a beginning of performance
  benchmarking framework.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>t/Makefile is adjusted to prevent newer versions of GNU make from
  running tests in seemingly random order.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The code to check if a path points at a file beyond a symbolic link
  has been restructured to be thread-safe.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>When pruning directories that has become empty during "git prune"
  and "git prune-packed", call closedir() that iterates over a
  directory before rmdir() it.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Build with NO_PERL_MAKEMAKER was broken and Git::I18N did not work
  with versions of Perl older than 5.8.3.
  (merge 5eb660e ab/perl-i18n later to maint).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git tag -s" honored "gpg.program" configuration variable since
  1.7.9, but "git tag -v" and "git verify-tag" didn't.
  (merge a2c2506 az/verify-tag-use-gpg-config later to maint).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"configure" script learned to take "--with-sane-tool-path" from the
  command line to record SANE_TOOL_PATH (used to avoid broken platform
  tools in /usr/bin) in config.mak.autogen.  This may be useful for
  people on Solaris who have saner tools outside /usr/xpg[46]/bin.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>zsh port of bash completion script needed another workaround.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>git-gui updated to 0.16.0.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>git-p4 (in contrib/) updates.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Git uses gettext to translate its most common interface messages
  into the user's language if translations are available and the
  locale is appropriately set. Distributors can drop new PO files
  in po/ to add new translations.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The code to handle username/password for HTTP transactions used in
  "git push" &amp; "git fetch" learned to talk "credential API" to
  external programs to cache or store them, to allow integration with
  platform native keychain mechanisms.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The input prompts in the terminal use our own getpass() replacement
  when possible. HTTP transactions used to ask for the username without
  echoing back what was typed, but with this change you will see it as
  you type.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The internals of "revert/cherry-pick" have been tweaked to prepare
  building more generic "sequencer" on top of the implementation that
  drives them.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git rev-parse FETCH_HEAD" after "git fetch" without specifying
  what to fetch from the command line will now show the commit that
  would be merged if the command were "git pull".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git add" learned to stream large files directly into a packfile
  instead of writing them into individual loose object files.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git checkout -B <current branch> <elsewhere>" is a more intuitive
  way to spell "git reset --keep <elsewhere>".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git checkout" and "git merge" learned "--no-overwrite-ignore" option
  to tell Git that untracked and ignored files are not expendable.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git commit --amend" learned "--no-edit" option to say that the
  user is amending the tree being recorded, without updating the
  commit log message.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git commit" and "git reset" re-learned the optimization to prime
  the cache-tree information in the index, which makes it faster to
  write a tree object out after the index entries are updated.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git commit" detects and rejects an attempt to stuff NUL byte in
  the commit log message.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git commit" learned "-S" to GPG-sign the commit; this can be shown
  with the "--show-signature" option to "git log".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>fsck and prune are relatively lengthy operations that still go
  silent while making the end-user wait. They learned to give progress
  output like other slow operations.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The set of built-in function-header patterns for various languages
  knows MATLAB.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git log --format='<format>'" learned new %g[nNeE] specifiers to
  show information from the reflog entries when walking the reflog
  (i.e. with "-g").</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git pull" can be used to fetch and merge an annotated/signed tag,
  instead of the tip of a topic branch. The GPG signature from the
  signed tag is recorded in the resulting merge commit for later
  auditing.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git log" learned "--show-signature" option to show the signed tag
  that was merged that is embedded in the merge commit. It also can
  show the signature made on the commit with "git commit -S".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git branch --edit-description" can be used to add descriptive text
  to explain what a topic branch is about.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git fmt-merge-msg" learned to take the branch description into
  account when preparing a merge summary that "git merge" records
  when merging a local branch.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git request-pull" has been updated to convey more information
  useful for integrators to decide if a topic is worth merging and
  what is pulled is indeed what the requestor asked to pull,
  including:</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>the tip of the branch being requested to be merged;</p>
</li>
<li>the branch description describing what the topic is about;</li>
<li>
<p>the contents of the annotated tag, when requesting to pull a tag.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git pull" learned to notice 'pull.rebase' configuration variable,
  which serves as a global fallback for setting 'branch.<name>.rebase'
  configuration variable per branch.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git tag" learned "--cleanup" option to control how the whitespaces
  and empty lines in tag message are cleaned up.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"gitweb" learned to show side-by-side diff.</p>
</li>
</ul>]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name></name>
      <uri>http://www.gitfr.net/blog</uri>
    </author>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git 1.7.9 publiée]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2012/01/28/git-1.7.9-publiee" />
    <id>http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2012/01/28/git-1.7.9-publiee</id>
    <updated>2012-01-28T21:13:00Z</updated>
    <published>2012-01-28T21:13:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.gitfr.net/blog" term="release" />
    <category scheme="http://www.gitfr.net/blog" term="git" />
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Git 1.7.9 publiée]]></summary>
    <content type="html" xml:base="http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2012/01/28/git-1.7.9-publiee"><![CDATA[<p>La version 1.7.9 est sortie le 27 janvier avec plusieurs évolutions
intéressantes : </p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Un meilleur support des gros fichiers (Git n'étant pas réputé pour ça).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>La signature des commits, qui fait suite au piratage de la machine qui 
  héberge le dépôt Git du projet Linux de Linus Torvalds.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>L'internationalisation est maintenant activée (honte à moi, toujours pas
  démarré le projet de traduction en Français).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>La possibilité d'ajouter une description à une branche.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>L'option <code>--no-edit</code> quand on amende un commit. </p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Je vous laisse comme d'habitude lire le changelog mais je trouve cette version
bien excitente ! J'attends la mise à jour sur ma machine pour faire quelques
tests.</p>
<h2>Le changelog</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>gitk updates accumulated since early 2011.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>git-gui updated to 0.16.0.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>git-p4 (in contrib/) updates.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Git uses gettext to translate its most common interface messages
  into the user's language if translations are available and the
  locale is appropriately set. Distributors can drop new PO files
  in po/ to add new translations.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The code to handle username/password for HTTP transactions used in
  "git push" &amp; "git fetch" learned to talk "credential API" to
  external programs to cache or store them, to allow integration with
  platform native keychain mechanisms.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The input prompts in the terminal use our own getpass() replacement
  when possible. HTTP transactions used to ask for the username without
  echoing back what was typed, but with this change you will see it as
  you type.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The internals of "revert/cherry-pick" have been tweaked to prepare
  building more generic "sequencer" on top of the implementation that
  drives them.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git rev-parse FETCH_HEAD" after "git fetch" without specifying
  what to fetch from the command line will now show the commit that
  would be merged if the command were "git pull".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git add" learned to stream large files directly into a packfile
  instead of writing them into individual loose object files.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git checkout -B <current branch> <elsewhere>" is a more intuitive
  way to spell "git reset --keep <elsewhere>".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git checkout" and "git merge" learned "--no-overwrite-ignore" option
  to tell Git that untracked and ignored files are not expendable.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git commit --amend" learned "--no-edit" option to say that the
  user is amending the tree being recorded, without updating the
  commit log message.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git commit" and "git reset" re-learned the optimization to prime
  the cache-tree information in the index, which makes it faster to
  write a tree object out after the index entries are updated.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git commit" detects and rejects an attempt to stuff NUL byte in
  the commit log message.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git commit" learned "-S" to GPG-sign the commit; this can be shown
  with the "--show-signature" option to "git log".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>fsck and prune are relatively lengthy operations that still go
  silent while making the end-user wait. They learned to give progress
  output like other slow operations.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The set of built-in function-header patterns for various languages
  knows MATLAB.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git log --format='<format>'" learned new %g[nNeE] specifiers to
  show information from the reflog entries when walking the reflog
  (i.e. with "-g").</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git pull" can be used to fetch and merge an annotated/signed tag,
  instead of the tip of a topic branch. The GPG signature from the
  signed tag is recorded in the resulting merge commit for later
  auditing.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git log" learned "--show-signature" option to show the signed tag
  that was merged that is embedded in the merge commit. It also can
  show the signature made on the commit with "git commit -S".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git branch --edit-description" can be used to add descriptive text
  to explain what a topic branch is about.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git fmt-merge-msg" learned to take the branch description into
  account when preparing a merge summary that "git merge" records
  when merging a local branch.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git request-pull" has been updated to convey more information
  useful for integrators to decide if a topic is worth merging and
  what is pulled is indeed what the requestor asked to pull,
  including:</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>the tip of the branch being requested to be merged;</p>
</li>
<li>the branch description describing what the topic is about;</li>
<li>
<p>the contents of the annotated tag, when requesting to pull a tag.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git pull" learned to notice 'pull.rebase' configuration variable,
   which serves as a global fallback for setting 'branch.<name>.rebase'
   configuration variable per branch.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git tag" learned "--cleanup" option to control how the whitespaces
   and empty lines in tag message are cleaned up.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"gitweb" learned to show side-by-side diff.</p>
</li>
</ul>]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name></name>
      <uri>http://www.gitfr.net/blog</uri>
    </author>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git 1.7.8 publiée]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2011/12/11/git-1.7.8-publiee" />
    <id>http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2011/12/11/git-1.7.8-publiee</id>
    <updated>2011-12-11T23:13:00Z</updated>
    <published>2011-12-11T23:13:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.gitfr.net/blog" term="release" />
    <category scheme="http://www.gitfr.net/blog" term="git" />
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Git 1.7.8 publiée]]></summary>
    <content type="html" xml:base="http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2011/12/11/git-1.7.8-publiee"><![CDATA[<p>La version 1.7.8 est sortie le 2 décembre. Comme vous pouvez constater, le
changelog est assez gros avec surtout de nouvelles options pour plusieurs
commandes et l'habituel lot de corrections.</p>
<h2>Le changelog</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Some git-svn, git-gui, git-p4 (in contrib) and msysgit updates.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Updates to bash completion scripts.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The build procedure has been taught to take advantage of computed
  dependency automatically when the complier supports it.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The date parser now accepts timezone designators that lack minutes
  part and also has a colon between "hh:mm".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The contents of the /etc/mailname file, if exists, is used as the
  default value of the hostname part of the committer/author e-mail.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git am" learned how to read from patches generated by Hg.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git archive" talking with a remote repository can report errors
  from the remote side in a more informative way.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git branch" learned an explicit --list option to ask for branches
  listed, optionally with a glob matching pattern to limit its output.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git check-attr" learned "--cached" option to look at .gitattributes
  files from the index, not from the working tree.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Variants of "git cherry-pick" and "git revert" that take multiple
  commits learned to "--continue" and "--abort".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git daemon" gives more human readble error messages to clients
  using ERR packets when appropriate.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Errors at the network layer is logged by "git daemon".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git diff" learned "--minimal" option to spend extra cycles to come
  up with a minimal patch output.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git diff" learned "--function-context" option to show the whole
  function as context that was affected by a change.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git difftool" can be told to skip launching the tool for a path by
  answering 'n' to its prompt.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git fetch" learned to honor transfer.fsckobjects configuration to
  validate the objects that were received from the other end, just like
  "git receive-pack" (the receiving end of "git push") does.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git fetch" makes sure that the set of objects it received from the
  other end actually completes the history before updating the refs.
  "git receive-pack" (the receiving end of "git push") learned to do the
  same.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git fetch" learned that fetching/cloning from a regular file on the
  filesystem is not necessarily a request to unpack a bundle file; the
  file could be ".git" with "gitdir: <path>" in it.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git for-each-ref" learned "%(contents:subject)", "%(contents:body)"
  and "%(contents:signature)". The last one is useful for signed tags.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git grep" used to incorrectly pay attention to .gitignore files
  scattered in the directory it was working in even when "--no-index"
  option was used. It no longer does this. The "--exclude-standard"
  option needs to be given to explicitly activate the ignore
  mechanism.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git grep" learned "--untracked" option, where given patterns are
   searched in untracked (but not ignored) files as well as tracked
   files in the working tree, so that matches in new but not yet
   added files do not get missed.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The recursive merge backend no longer looks for meaningless
  existing merges in submodules unless in the outermost merge.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git log" and friends learned "--children" option.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git ls-remote" learned to respond to "-h"(elp) requests.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"mediawiki" remote helper can interact with (surprise!) MediaWiki
  with "git fetch" &amp; "git push".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git merge" learned the "--edit" option to allow users to edit the
  merge commit log message.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git rebase -i" can be told to use special purpose editor suitable
  only for its insn sheet via sequence.editor configuration variable.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git send-email" learned to respond to "-h"(elp) requests.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git send-email" allows the value given to sendemail.aliasfile to begin
  with "~/" to refer to the $HOME directory.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git send-email" forces use of Authen::SASL::Perl to work around
  issues between Authen::SASL::Cyrus and AUTH PLAIN/LOGIN.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git stash" learned "--include-untracked" option to stash away
  untracked/ignored cruft from the working tree.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git submodule clone" does not leak an error message to the UI
  level unnecessarily anymore.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git submodule update" learned to honor "none" as the value for
  submodule.<name>.update to specify that the named submodule should
  not be checked out by default.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>When populating a new submodule directory with "git submodule init",
  the $GIT_DIR metainformation directory for submodules is created inside
  $GIT_DIR/modules/<name>/ directory of the superproject and referenced
  via the gitfile mechanism. This is to make it possible to switch
  between commits in the superproject that has and does not have the
  submodule in the tree without re-cloning.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"gitweb" leaked unescaped control characters from syntax hiliter
  outputs.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"gitweb" can be told to give custom string at the end of the HTML
  HEAD element.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"gitweb" now has its own manual pages.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>HTTP transport did not use pushurl correctly, and also did not tell
  what host it is trying to authenticate with when asking for
  credentials.
  (merge deba493 jk/http-auth later to maint).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git blame" was aborted if started from an uncommitted content and
  the path had the textconv filter in effect.
  (merge 8518088 ss/blame-textconv-fake-working-tree later to maint).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Adding many refs to the local repository in one go (e.g. "git fetch"
  that fetches many tags) and looking up a ref by name in a repository
  with too many refs were unnecessarily slow.
  (merge 17d68a54d jp/get-ref-dir-unsorted later to maint).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Report from "git commit" on untracked files was confused under
  core.ignorecase option.
  (merge 395c7356 jk/name-hash-dirent later to maint).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git merge" did not understand ":/<pattern>" as a way to name a commit.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git push" on the receiving end used to call post-receive and post-update
  hooks for attempted removal of non-existing refs.
  (merge 160b81ed ph/push-to-delete-nothing later to maint).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Help text for "git remote set-url" and "git remote set-branches"
  were misspelled.
  (merge c49904e fc/remote-seturl-usage-fix later to maint).
  (merge 656cdf0 jc/remote-setbranches-usage-fix later to maint).</p>
</li>
</ul>]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name></name>
      <uri>http://www.gitfr.net/blog</uri>
    </author>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git 1.7.7 publiée]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2011/10/01/git-1.7.7-publiee" />
    <id>http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2011/10/01/git-1.7.7-publiee</id>
    <updated>2011-10-01T10:34:00Z</updated>
    <published>2011-10-01T10:34:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.gitfr.net/blog" term="release" />
    <category scheme="http://www.gitfr.net/blog" term="git" />
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Git 1.7.7 publiée]]></summary>
    <content type="html" xml:base="http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2011/10/01/git-1.7.7-publiee"><![CDATA[<p>Reprenons la bonne habitude d'annoncer les nouvelles versions. Rien de bien
méchant dans cette 1.7.7, il faut attendre la 1.8 je pense pour des plus gros
changements.</p>
<h2>Le changelog</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>The scripting part of the codebase is getting prepared for i18n/l10n.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Interix, Cygwin and Minix ports got updated.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Various updates to git-p4 (in contrib/), fast-import, and git-svn.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Gitweb learned to read from /etc/gitweb-common.conf when it exists,
  before reading from gitweb_config.perl or from /etc/gitweb.conf
  (this last one is read only when per-repository gitweb_config.perl
  does not exist).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Various codepaths that invoked zlib deflate/inflate assumed that these
  functions can compress or uncompress more than 4GB data in one call on
  platforms with 64-bit long, which has been corrected.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Git now recognizes loose objects written by other implementations that
  use a non-standard window size for zlib deflation (e.g. Agit running on
  Android with 4kb window). We used to reject anything that was not
  deflated with 32kb window.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Interaction between the use of pager and coloring of the output has
  been improved, especially when a command that is not built-in was
  involved.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git am" learned to pass the "--exclude=<path>" option through to underlying
  "git apply".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>You can now feed many empty lines before feeding an mbox file to
  "git am".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git archive" can be told to pass the output to gzip compression and
  produce "archive.tar.gz".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git bisect" can be used in a bare repository (provided that the test
  you perform per each iteration does not need a working tree, of
  course).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The length of abbreviated object names in "git branch -v" output
  now honors the core.abbrev configuration variable.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git check-attr" can take relative paths from the command line.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git check-attr" learned an "--all" option to list the attributes for a
  given path.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git checkout" (both the code to update the files upon checking out a
  different branch and the code to checkout a specific set of files) learned
  to stream the data from object store when possible, without having to
  read the entire contents of a file into memory first. An earlier round
  of this code that is not in any released version had a large leak but
  now it has been plugged.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git clone" can now take a "--config key=value" option to set the
  repository configuration options that affect the initial checkout.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git commit <paths>..." now lets you feed relative pathspecs that
  refer to outside your current subdirectory.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git diff --stat" learned a --stat-count option to limit the output of
  a diffstat report.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git diff" learned a "--histogram" option to use a different diff
  generation machinery stolen from jgit, which might give better
  performance.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git diff" had a weird worst case behaviour that can be triggered
  when comparing files with potentially many places that could match.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git fetch", "git push" and friends no longer show connection
  errors for addresses that couldn't be connected to when at least one
  address succeeds (this is arguably a regression but a deliberate
  one).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git grep" learned "--break" and "--heading" options, to let users mimic
  the output format of "ack".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git grep" learned a "-W" option that shows wider context using the same
  logic used by "git diff" to determine the hunk header.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Invoking the low-level "git http-fetch" without "-a" option (which
  git itself never did---normal users should not have to worry about
  this) is now deprecated.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The "--decorate" option to "git log" and its family learned to
  highlight grafted and replaced commits.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git rebase master topci" no longer spews usage hints after giving
  the "fatal: no such branch: topci" error message.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The recursive merge strategy implementation got a fairly large
  fix for many corner cases that may rarely happen in real world
  projects (it has been verified that none of the 16000+ merges in
  the Linux kernel history back to v2.6.12 is affected with the
  corner case bugs this update fixes).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git stash" learned an "--include-untracked option".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git submodule update" used to stop at the first error updating a
  submodule; it now goes on to update other submodules that can be
  updated, and reports the ones with errors at the end.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git push" can be told with the "--recurse-submodules=check" option to
  refuse pushing of the supermodule, if any of its submodules'
  commits hasn't been pushed out to their remotes.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git upload-pack" and "git receive-pack" learned to pretend that only a
  subset of the refs exist in a repository. This may help a site to
  put many tiny repositories into one repository (this would not be
  useful for larger repositories as repacking would be problematic).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git verify-pack" has been rewritten to use the "index-pack" machinery
  that is more efficient in reading objects in packfiles.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>test scripts for gitweb tried to run even when CGI-related perl modules
  are not installed; they now exit early when the latter are unavailable.</p>
</li>
</ul>]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name></name>
      <uri>http://www.gitfr.net/blog</uri>
    </author>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git 1.7.6.1 publiée]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2011/08/29/git-1.7.6.1-publiee" />
    <id>http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2011/08/29/git-1.7.6.1-publiee</id>
    <updated>2011-08-29T00:34:00Z</updated>
    <published>2011-08-29T00:34:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.gitfr.net/blog" term="release" />
    <category scheme="http://www.gitfr.net/blog" term="git" />
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Git 1.7.6.1 publiée]]></summary>
    <content type="html" xml:base="http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2011/08/29/git-1.7.6.1-publiee"><![CDATA[<p>La première version de maintenance de la branche 1.7.6.x est sortie le 24 août,
avec 88 corrections.</p>
<h2>Le changelog</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Various codepaths that invoked zlib deflate/inflate assumed that these
   functions can compress or uncompress more than 4GB data in one call on
   platforms with 64-bit long, which has been corrected.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git unexecutable" reported that "unexecutable" was not found, even
   though the actual error was that "unexecutable" was found but did
   not have a proper she-bang line to be executed.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Error exits from $PAGER were silently ignored.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git checkout -b <branch>" was confused when attempting to create a
   branch whose name ends with "-g" followed by hexadecimal digits,
   and refused to work.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git checkout -b <branch>" sometimes wrote a bogus reflog entry,
   causing later "git checkout -" to fail.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git diff --cc" learned to correctly ignore binary files.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git diff -c/--cc" mishandled a deletion that resolves a conflict, and
   looked in the working tree instead.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git fast-export" forgot to quote pathnames with unsafe characters
   in its output.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git fetch" over smart-http transport used to abort when the
   repository was updated between the initial connection and the
   subsequent object transfer.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git fetch" did not recurse into submodules in subdirectories.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git ls-tree" did not error out when asked to show a corrupt tree.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git pull" without any argument left an extra whitespace after the
   command name in its reflog.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git push --quiet" was not really quiet.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git rebase -i -p" incorrectly dropped commits from side branches.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git reset [<commit>] paths..." did not reset the index entry correctly
   for unmerged paths.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git submodule add" did not allow a relative repository path when
   the superproject did not have any default remote url.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git submodule foreach" failed to correctly give the standard input to
   the user-supplied command it invoked.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>submodules that the user has never showed interest in by running
   "git submodule init" was incorrectly marked as interesting by "git
   submodule sync".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git submodule update --quiet" was not really quiet.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git tag -l <glob>..." did not take multiple glob patterns from the
   command line.</p>
</li>
</ul>]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name></name>
      <uri>http://www.gitfr.net/blog</uri>
    </author>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git 1.7.6 publiée]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2011/07/09/git-1.7.6-publiee" />
    <id>http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2011/07/09/git-1.7.6-publiee</id>
    <updated>2011-07-09T20:34:00Z</updated>
    <published>2011-07-09T20:34:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.gitfr.net/blog" term="release" />
    <category scheme="http://www.gitfr.net/blog" term="git" />
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Git 1.7.6 publiée]]></summary>
    <content type="html" xml:base="http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2011/07/09/git-1.7.6-publiee"><![CDATA[<p>Nouvelle fournée pour Git avec cette branche 1.7.6.x. A noter que c'est la
première version qui respecte le nouveau cycle de release plus court voulu
par Junio.</p>
<p>A la lecture du changelog, voici quelques points que je remarque :</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Le magic pathspec ":/".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>L'option patch pour la commande git-commit.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>La possibilité d'utiliser les expressions rationnelles pour git-grep.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>La variable de configuration <code>merge.ff</code> pour spécifier s'il faut toujours
   ou jamais faire un commit de merge.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Ne pas spécifier de branche à git-rebase signifie rebaser sur upstream.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2>Changelog</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Various git-svn updates.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Updates the way content tags are handled in gitweb.  Also adds
  a UI to choose common timezone for displaying the dates.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Similar to branch names, tagnames that begin with "-" are now
  disallowed.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Clean-up of the C part of i18n (but not l10n---please wait)
  continues.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The scripting part of the codebase is getting prepared for i18n/l10n.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Pushing and pulling from a repository with large number of refs that
  point to identical commits are optimized by not listing the same commit
  during the common ancestor negotiation exchange with the other side.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Adding a file larger than core.bigfilethreshold (defaults to 1/2 Gig)
  using "git add" will send the contents straight to a packfile without
  having to hold it and its compressed representation both at the same
  time in memory.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Processes spawned by "[alias] <name> = !process" in the configuration
  can inspect <code>GIT_PREFIX</code> environment variable to learn where in the
  working tree the original command was invoked.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A magic pathspec ":/" tells a command that limits its operation to
  the current directory when ran from a subdirectory to work on the
  entire working tree. In general, ":/path/to/file" would be relative
  to the root of the working tree hierarchy.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>After "git reset --hard; edit Makefile; cd t/", "git add -u" would
  be a no-op, but "git add -u :/" would add the updated contents of
  the Makefile at the top level. If you want to name a path in the
  current subdirectory whose unusual name begins with ":/", you can
  name it by "./:/that/path" or by "\:/that/path".</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>"git blame" learned "--abbrev[=<n>]" option to control the minimum
  number of hexdigits shown for commit object names.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git blame" learned "--line-porcelain" that is less efficient but is
  easier to parse.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Aborting "git commit --interactive" discards updates to the index
  made during the interactive session.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git commit" learned a "--patch" option to directly jump to the
  per-hunk selection UI of the interactive mode.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git diff" and its family of commands learned --dirstat=0 to show
  directories that contribute less than 0.1% of changes.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git diff" and its family of commands learned --dirstat=lines mode to
  assess damage to the directory based on number of lines in the patch
  output, not based on the similarity numbers.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git format-patch" learned "--quiet" option to suppress the output of
  the names of generated files.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git format-patch" quotes people's names when it has RFC822 special
  characters in it, e.g. "Junio C. Hamano" <a href="&#109;&#97;&#105;&#108;&#116;&#111;&#58;&#106;&#99;&#104;&#64;&#101;&#120;&#97;&#109;&#112;&#108;&#101;&#46;&#99;&#111;&#109;">&#106;&#99;&#104;&#64;&#101;&#120;&#97;&#109;&#112;&#108;&#101;&#46;&#99;&#111;&#109;</a>.  Earlier
  it was up to the user to do this when using its output.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git format-patch" can take an empty --subject-prefix now.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git grep" learned the "-P" option to take pcre regular expressions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git log" and friends learned a new "--notes" option to replace the
  "--show-notes" option.  Unlike "--show-notes", "--notes=<ref>" does
  not imply showing the default notes.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>They also learned a log.abbrevCommit configuration variable to augment
  the --abbrev-commit command line option.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git ls-remote" learned "--exit-code" option to consider it a
  different kind of error when no remote ref to be shown.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git merge" learned "-" as a short-hand for "the previous branch", just
  like the way "git checkout -" works.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git merge" uses "merge.ff" configuration variable to decide to always
  create a merge commit (i.e. --no-ff, aka merge.ff=no), refuse to create
  a merge commit (i.e. --ff-only, aka merge.ff=only). Setting merge.ff=yes
  (or not setting it at all) restores the default behaviour of allowing
  fast-forward to happen when possible.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>p4-import (from contrib) learned a new option --preserve-user.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git read-tree -m" learned "--dry-run" option that reports if a merge
  would fail without touching the index nor the working tree.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git rebase" that does not specify on top of which branch to rebase
  the current branch now uses @{upstream} of the current branch.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git rebase" finished either normally or with --abort did not
  update the reflog for HEAD to record the event to come back to
  where it started from.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git remote add -t only-this-branch --mirror=fetch" is now allowed. Earlier
  a fetch-mode mirror meant mirror everything, but now it only means refs are
  not renamed.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git rev-list --count" used with "--cherry-mark" counts the cherry-picked
  commits separately, producing more a useful output.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git submodule update" learned "--force" option to get rid of local
  changes in submodules and replace them with the up-to-date version.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git status" and friends ignore .gitmodules file while the file is
  still in a conflicted state during a merge, to avoid using information
  that is not final and possibly corrupt with conflict markers.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git config" used to choke with an insanely long line.
  (merge ef/maint-strbuf-init later)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git diff --quiet" did not work well with --diff-filter.
  (merge jk/diff-not-so-quick later)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git status -z" did not default to --porcelain output format.
  (merge bc/maint-status-z-to-use-porcelain later)</p>
</li>
</ul>]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name></name>
      <uri>http://www.gitfr.net/blog</uri>
    </author>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git 1.7.5.4 publiée]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2011/06/13/git-1.7.5.4-publiee" />
    <id>http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2011/06/13/git-1.7.5.4-publiee</id>
    <updated>2011-06-13T02:10:00Z</updated>
    <published>2011-06-13T02:10:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.gitfr.net/blog" term="release" />
    <category scheme="http://www.gitfr.net/blog" term="git" />
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Git 1.7.5.4 publiée]]></summary>
    <content type="html" xml:base="http://www.gitfr.net/blog/2011/06/13/git-1.7.5.4-publiee"><![CDATA[<p>La quatrième version de la branche 1.7.5.x est sortie le 2 juin, soit seulement 5 jours aprés la précédente. C'est la dernière ligne du changelog qui nous donne la réponse.</p>
<h2>Changelog</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>The single-key mode of "git add -p" was easily fooled into thinking
  that it was told to add everthing ('a') when up-arrow was pressed by
  mistake.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Setting a git command that uses custom configuration via "-c var=val"
  as an alias caused a crash due to a realloc(3) failure.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git diff -C -C" used to disable the rename detection entirely when
  there are too many copy candidate paths in the tree; now it falls
  back to "-C" when doing so would keep the copy candidate paths
  under the rename detection limit.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>"git rerere" did not diagnose a corrupt MERGE_RR file in some cases.</p>
</li>
</ul>]]></content>
  </entry>
</feed>
